(日向翔陽)すみません
田中さんすみません
Sorry!
I'm so sorry, Tanaka!
(田中)いいつてんだろうが
I told you not to worry about it.
そんなことより
おめぇは大丈夫なのかよ
Forget me, are you all right?
はい途中休んだし
バス降りたら平気です
Yeah.
Lying down helped. I feel fine now that I'm off the bus.
(田中)そうかならいい
今日の試合は
That so?
Good.
Our match today rests on your shoulders, after all.
お前の働きに懸かてるかんな
は
３対３のときみたく
俺にフリで打たしてくれよ
Let me spike freely like you did in the three-on-three.
(菅原)田中プレシャダメ
(田中)えなんすか
Hey, Tanaka!
No pressure!
Huh? What?
ががん頑張り
I'll... I'll do my...
ぐトトイレ行てきます
I-I need to use the bathroom.
(田中)
上の次は下か忙しいヤツだなぁ
First the top, now the bottom?
Never a moment's rest for you, huh?
(影山飛雄)
あいつまた情けねぇな
Not again.
Pathetic!
一発気合い入れて
(菅原)おい何言てんのお前
Time to beat him into shape.
What are you saying?
日向はそういうのが
効くタイプじゃないだろ
You know that won't work on Hinata!
やてみないと分かりませんよ
(菅原)田中この単細胞押さえろ
We won't know until we try.
Tanaka, help me stop this fool!
(澤村)はぁ
一発だけ
Okay!
Knock it off!
Just once...
カァ
Episode Six:
An Amusing Team
(矢巾)なあ
今日来る烏野てさ
So...
We're playing Karasuno today, right?
あれがいるとこだろ
(金田一)え
Doesn't he go to that school?
(矢巾)コト上の王様
お前出身中学同じだろ
The King of the Court, I mean.
Didn't you two go to the same junior high, Kindaichi?
金田一
(金田一)ああ影山すか
Oh, you mean Kageyama?
別に大したことないすよ
He's not all that special.
確かに個人技は
頭一つ抜けてましたけど
Sure, his individual skill may've been off the charts,
チムプレてもんが
根本的に向いてないんすよ
but he has no clue what it takes to succeed in a team sport.
あいつ自己中だから
He's too egocentric.
(矢巾)へえまあ
行た先が烏野だしな
Oh? Not like it matters now that he's gone to Karasuno.
昔は強かたのか
知らんけど
They may've been a strong team in the past or whatever,
烏野つたらマネが
美人てことくらいしか
but right now, all that comes to mind is that their manager's a real hottie.
覚えてないし
マジすか
For real?
Yeah.
(矢巾)そうなのよ
ちょとエロい感じでさぁ
Shimizu, I think we're good to go.
She's got this sultry look to her.
Right.
ああとそういや
ガラの悪いヤツいたなぁ
Oh, they also have this punk on their team.
坊主で目つき悪くてさ
あたま悪そうな顔した
A cueball with a real mean look.
He looks completely retarded.
ふん
(矢巾)う
Oh?
あえと
Uh...
(田中)
うちをあんまなめてと
Keep looking down on us...
(田中)食い散らかすぞ
and we'll eat you alive.
(月島)そんな威嚇しちゃ
ダメですよ田中さん
You shouldn't threaten them like that, Tanaka.
ほらエリトの方々が
びくりしちゃて
Look, now these poor elites are shaking in their boots. Don't you feel sorry for them?
かわいそうじゃないですか
べ別にビビてねぇよ
L-Like hell we are!
≪あのメガネ誰だ
Who's the four-eyes?
あんなタパのヤツ
烏野にいたか
I don't remember Karasuno having such a tall player.
(田中)おうそうだな
I guess.
いじめんのは
試合中だけにしてやんねぇとな
Gotta limit the bullying to the match proper, right?
(澤村)あお前ら
ちょと目ぇ離した隙に
You guys!
Can't take my eyes off you for a second!
We're sorry!
失礼しました
(矢巾)あいえ
D-Don't be.
(澤村)田中その顔やめろ
Knock it off, Tanaka!
(金田一)久しぶりじゃねぇの王様
(澤村)ん
Long time no see, King.
(金田一)そちでどんな独裁政権
敷いてんのか楽しみにしてるわ
Show me what kinda dictatorship you've put in place this time.
I can hardly wait.
Sure.
バシ
痛何するんすか
What's gotten into him?
なんだあいつ
おとなしいフリしやがて
What was that for?
He's acting all calm and collected.
You've grown up, eh?
Gymnasium #3
ででかい体育館も人も
M-Massive!
B-Both the gym and the players!
(澤村)挨拶
(一同)お願いします
Greet them!
Let's have a good match!
(一同)お願いします
守備も攻撃も全員の能力が
Aoba Jousai is a team whose players are all
extremely good at both offense and defense.
平均して高いのが青葉城西だ
よそ行たらどこでも
ｴｰｽ張れるようなヤツがそろてる
It's full of guys who would be the star player on any other team.
(菅原)
ブロク強力で有名だしな
Plus they're famous as being great blockers.
(田中)
どうしたんすか二人とも
What's gotten into you two?
それひかき回すための
日向じゃないすかなあ
We've got Hinata here to throw a spanner in their works!
Right?
まお前が下手くそなのは
分かてからカバは任せろ
But we know that you suck, so we've got your back.
あ
(２人)お
(田中)あでもサブ
打つときだけは一人だからな
Oh, but you'll be on your own while serving.
ミスんなよ
(２人)ば
Don't you dare screw up.
はははは冗談だ冗談
サブミスくらいなんてことねぇ
Just kidding!
Who cares if you mess up a serve here and there?
お前は何も心配しないで
ガンガン
You don't have to worry about a thing. Just—
あれ日向どこ行た
(山口)トイレ行きましたよ
Where'd Hinata go?
To the bathroom.
Not again!
(田中)またかよ
Save
water
うぅやべぇ
Ugh, this is bad.
≫(矢巾)なんだよ烏野の連中
態度ばかでかくてよ
The hell's Karasuno's problem?
Acting like they're hot shit.
(金田一)そすね
(２人)あ
Yeah.
≪こいつ中学の試合で
影山の隣にいたヤツ≫
This guy...
He was the one standing next to Kageyama when I faced him in junior high.
≪らきょうみたいなシルエト
覚えてる≫
I remember his turnip head.
あお前烏野の１年
そそうだけど
Are you a first-year at Karasuno?
Yeah. What of it?
(金田一)へえじゃあ
影山はどうようちの王様は
How do you like playing with Kageyama, our king?
相変わらず偉そうだたけど
そんなんじゃねぇ
He still seems to be up on his high horse.
You've gotta be kidding me!
偉そうなんてもんじゃねぇんだよ
It goes way beyond that!
影山大王の独裁のもと
俺という臣民は虐げられ
Under the iron-fisted rule of Kageyama the Great,
plebeians like me are cruelly oppressed,
日々苦渋を味わているんだ
our lives filled with suffering!
ちょとうまいからて
調子に乗りやがて
He acts like he's God's gift to humanity
just because he happens to be kinda good!
ほらね
ははすげぇ嫌われよう
See?
He sure does hate the guy.
レシブもブロクもサブも
うまいことはうまいんですよ
He is pretty good at receiving, blocking, and serving.
そうそう腹立つ
Yeah. It's enough to piss you off.
But he's awful at setting.
And he's amazing at setting.
でもトスだけは最悪
でトスが特にすげぇ
トスが
すげぇ
At setting?
He's amazing.
(金田一)ああ
お前実際の試合で影山のトス
Oh, I know. You've never spiked his sets in an actual match before, have you?
打たことないんだろ
ありゃひどいよ
They're awful.
打ちづらいたらねぇの
えそうなの
"Difficult to spike" is an understatement.
Really?
(金田一)あいつは
自己中の王様だからな
He's called the egocentric king for a reason.
セタのくせに
スパイカに打たせるていう
He fails to do the most obvious thing that's expected of him as a setter: helping the spiker hit the ball.
当然のことができてねぇんだ
影山にとて必要なのは
What he finds essential is pawns that'll move according to his will.
自分の思いどおりに動く
駒なんだよ
自分が勝つために
いらないものはポイ
And he throws away anything he doesn't need to win.
(田中)ふふふふ
(２人)え
影山が中学のままかどうかは
Decide whether Kageyama's still the same as he was in junior high after you've watched him play, turnip head.
試合で見てみろよらきょう君
(金田一)はあ
(田中)なあ日向
Right, Hinata?
≪自分が勝つために
いらないものはポイか≫
He throws away anything he doesn't need to win, huh?
≪もし影山の前で
ヘマやらかしたら
If I mess up in front of Kageyama...
引込め役立たず
ぐえ
Get outta here! You're useless!
≪選手交代
ギュルギュル
...I'll be subbed out!
ちょおなか痛い
(田中)え
My tummy hurts!
(金田一)
じゃあ楽しみにしてますね
Okay, then. I'm looking forward to it.
うぅ
(澤村)日向
Don't be so nervous, Hinata.
緊張しなくて大丈夫だから
リラクス
Relax.
はいリラクス頑張ります
Okay!
I'll do my best to relax!
Hurry up and change, Hinata.
なあマネから１年に
気の利いたひと言ない
Hey, could you say something to cheer that first-year up?
Okay!
(清水)ねえちょと
え
Could I talk to you for a sec?
(清水)期待してる
I have high hopes for you.
う
(清水)え
≪とどめを刺してしまた
すまん日向≫
She finished him off!
Forgive me, Hinata.
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
(主審)それでは
烏野高校対青葉城西高校の
The practice match between Karasuno High and Aoba Jousai High will now begin.
練習試合を始めます
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
(金田一)さきのチビ
ミドルブロカかよ
That midget's playing middle blocker?
なんの間違いだ
(岩泉)ほんとに影山だ
You can't be serious.
It really is Kageyama.
なんで烏野に
(矢巾)さあ
What's he doing at Karasuno?
Beats me.
(澤村)おい日向しかりしろ
ははい
Pull yourself together, Hinata!
Okay!
I'll do my best to pull myself together!
しかりするのを頑張ります
(澤村)いやとにかく落ち着け
That's not—
Look, just calm down.
おい日向分かてんな
Hey, Hinata!
You get it, don't you?
この前の３対３と同じ感じで
わ分かてる
Play like you did during the three-on-three.
I-I get it!
ほんとか
Do you?
(岩泉)松川ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Matsukawa!
オライ任せろ
ああ
Okay, I got this!
バカかどう見ても
おめぇのボルじゃねぇだろ
Are you retarded? That clearly wasn't yours!
ごめんなさい
(澤村)縁下カバ
I'm sorry!
Take care of it, Ennoshita!
(縁下)田中
おお
Tanaka!
Got it!
(金田一)まずは一本
(田中)んん
That's one down.
(澤村)ドンマイドンマイ日向
落ち着いて周りも見ていこうな
Don't worry about it.
Hinata, calm down and look around you.
すみません
I'm sorry!
He's totally overwhelmed.
≪こいつ完全にのまれてる≫
おお
うぎ
(澤村)日向
Hinata!
一回落ち着こうな
Just calm down, okay?
ピ
(田中)おしゃ
ラキラキ
Hell yeah! That was lucky!
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
タチネトか
やと烏野も点が動いたよ
A net foul, huh?
Karasuno finally scored a point.
てめぇ
いいかげんその緊張やめろ
Enough with the nerves already, damn it!
ははやぱり
大したことねぇじゃねぇか
I'm sorry!
Give me one more chance!
Yeah, he really isn't all that special.
(国見)全く変わてないな
He hasn't changed one bit.
よし
確実に１点ずつ返していこう
All right!
Let's make a comeback, one point at a time!
次のサブはあ
≪よりによて
Who's serving next?
This is the worst possible timing.
このタイミングで日向のサブ≫
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
Hinata has to serve now?
≪サブミスは即失点≫
A service error means the opposition score.
Relax, Hinata!
≪これをミスたら
１セト目が終わる≫
So if I mess this up, they'll win the first set!
(田中)影山あいつの呼吸
止まてねぇか大丈夫か
Kageyama, I don't think he's breathing.
Is he gonna be okay?
俺に言われても
分かんないすよ
Don't ask me.
((勝つために
いらないものはポイ))
He throws away anything he doesn't need to win.
≪絶対にヘマすんな
ヘマしたら下げられる≫
Don't screw up.
I'll get subbed out if I do!
≪落ち着け大丈夫大丈夫
Calm down.
It's okay. It's all right.
ピ
ひぃ
≪あヤバい
手にちゃんと当たてな
Shit! I didn't hit it cleanly!
ガン
ぐ
Haikyuu !!
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
(田中)わはははおい
Hey, is your head okay?
Boom, headshot!
(月島)ナイス後頭部
(田中)後頭部大丈夫か
Quit adding fuel to the fire!
(菅原)あおるなつうの
Knock it off, you guys!
(澤村)やめろお前ら
≪やてしまた≫
Now I've really done it.
(澤村)あおい影山
Hey, Kageyama...
あぁままま待て
W-Wait!
話せば分かる影山
Let's talk this out!
Kageyama!
なあちょと
Hey...
お前さ
はい
You know...
Yes?
What is it that's making you so nervous?
一体何にビビて
そんなに緊張してんの
Is it our opponents' size?
相手がでかいこと
初めての練習試合だから
Or because it's your first practice match?
俺の後頭部に
サブ打ち込む以上に
There's something you find scarier than
hitting a serve into the back of my head.
怖いことて
何
What is it?
特に思い当たりません
I can't think of anything.
じゃあもう
緊張する理由はないよなぁ
So there's no reason for you to be nervous anymore, is there?
I mean, you've already gone and done the worst thing possible.
もうやちまたもんなぁ
いちばん怖いこと
それじゃあ
In that case...
hurry up and go back to normal, dumbass!
ととと
通常運転に戻れバカ野郎
あれ今のヘマはセフ
Huh?
I got away with that?
ああなんの話だ
は
What are you talking about?
If I got away with that,
I could've gotten away with anything!
≪今のがｾｰﾌなら何やらかしても
大体大丈夫じゃねぇか
What the hell? That damn turnip head had me scared for a moment!
≪あのらきょうヘド
ビビらせやがて
≪うでも今俺のせいで
１セト目落としたんだた≫
But we just lost the first set because of me.
≪影山がよくても
Kageyama may've forgiven me, but...
Hey, Hinata.
(田中)おいこら日向
≪ひぃ
Eek!
Say...
お前
はい
Yes?
D'you think you have to play as well as the rest of us?
ほかのヤツみたいに上手に
やんなきゃとか思てんのか
Like you're good enough?
いちょ前に
ちゃちゃんとやらないと
But I'll get subbed out if I don't play well...
交代させられるから
I wanna play till the end!
俺最後まで試合に出たいから
(田中)おいなめるなよ
Hey, don't you dare look down on us!
お前が下手くそなことなんか
分かりきてることだろうが
We're well aware that you suck, man!
え
(田中)分かてて入れてんだろ
Daichi put you in the lineup despite being aware of that!
大地さんは
え
As for getting subbed out...
(田中)
交代させられたときのことはな
あうん
ん
交代させられたときに考えろ
Cross that bridge when you get to it!
ええ
(武田)た助けなくて平気
Quit racking your brain over something that might happen!
Shouldn't you stop him?
(菅原)
あはいたぶん大丈夫です
Oh, yeah. I think we're good.
Not like you have a brain, anyway!
Listen up.
(田中)いいか
バレボルつうのはな
In volleyball,
everyone on your side of the court is your ally, without exception!
ネトのこち側にいる全員
もれなく味方なんだよ
So what if you suck? Go ahead and cause trouble for us!
(田中)下手くそ上等
迷惑かけろ足を引張れ
Hold us back!
Making up for all those things...
それを補てやるための
is our job as your teammates and upperclassmen!
チムであり先輩だ
おお
(田中)ほれ田中先輩と呼べ
Now show me some respect.
田中先輩
(田中)はははは
Yes, sir!
Do it again.
I bet he just wants to be called "sir."
先輩て呼ばれたいだけだな
あれ
Yes, sir!
Yeah, but he's being a huge help.
うんでも
田中がいて助かた
ああいうことは絶対
裏表なさそうなヤツが言うから
A speech like that is only effective when delivered by someone who always speaks his mind.
Yes, sir!
効果があるんだよな
Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
(生徒)何何
What's going on?
練習試合だて
これから第２セトじゃん
A practice match, apparently.
The second set's starting now.
おいあとで
後頭部狙うサブ教えて
Hey, teach me how to hit a serve at someone's head after the match.
う
あ僕にもあとで教えてね
Me too.
ピ
(澤村)縁下ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Ennoshita.
Do the same thing you did in the three-on-three.
((この前の３対３と同じだ))
((お前は
相手のブロクのいない所へ
Run as fast as you can to an area they're not marking,
jump as high as you can,
and swing your arm as hard as you can.
マクスのスピドとジャンプで
跳んでスイング))
((ほかのスパイカと
ぶつかんないように
But be careful not to run into the other spikers.
気をつけろよ))
((おう))
Okay.
Kunimi!
(矢巾)国見
(国見)く
(田中)影山カバ
はい
Take care of it, Kageyama!
Okay.
Set it to the left!
レフト持てこい
(澤村)ライト
Right!
They're not gonna do a quick attack.
≪クイクはないなたぶん
またレフトかライトからの
It'll probably be an open shot from the left or right again.
オプン
≪なんだ
What the?
A quick attack?
≪クイク
Huh?
≪あれ手に当たんない≫
It didn't hit my hand.
ピ
≪クイクあんのか
They can do quick attacks?
Or was that just a bluff?
≪それともただのハタリ
でもまあどちみち
Either way...
今みたいなの
ちゃんと打てなきゃ
You'd better spike sets like that, lest you incur the King's wrath.
王様が怒りだすよ
う
Hinata.
日向
(金田一)ほらきた
Here it comes.
悪い今のトス少し高かた
My bad.
I set that too high.
影山が
謝た
Kageyama...
...apologized?
許してやらなくもない
I'll think about forgiving you.
Ow!
痛たたた
痛い痛ぇて影山ハゲる
Ouch! That hurts, Kageyama!
I'll go bald!
ピ
(岩泉)一本
Let's take this point.
Nice serve!
(縁下)オライ
オライ
Got it.
I got this!
≪ライトとセンタが動いた
レフトも待てる≫
The right wing spiker and setter are on the move!
Send it to me!
The left's waiting for it.
Who will Kageyama use?
≪影山は誰を使う
Now!
≪今ここだろ
This is it!
え
(２人)しゃ
All right!
Yeah!
(２人)おし
(菅原)よしゃ
Yes!
There it is.
出たよ変人トス＆スパイク
The freak set-and-spike.
(生徒たち)おお
(生徒)なんだ今の速ぇ
What the hell?
That was fast!
(澤村)日向影山
(田中･澤村)せの
Hinata, Kageyama.
One, two...
(一同)おおし
Yeah!
おおチチムぽい
(田中)ああ
It's like we're a team!
"Like a team"?
｢ぽい｣じゃなくてチムだろうが
We are a team.
Got it!
(澤村)ナイストス影山
あざす
Nice set, Kageyama.
Thank you.
That midget can do fast attacks?
(矢巾)
おいあのチビ速攻あんのか
Give us one more.
Sure.
Something's changed since the first set.
１セト目と様子違いますね
Okay, are you scared now?
≪よし
ビビたかビビたな≫
You are, right?
Keep your eyes locked on Hinata.
≪日向を存分に警戒しろよ≫
Now that Hinata's back to normal,
日向が動きだしたところで
反撃いきましょう
let's stage a comeback.
Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
チャンスボル
A chance!
Got it!
オライ
来るて分かてたら
It's not the least bit scary if we know what's coming!
怖くねぇんだよ
なんだとおら
Say what?
あ
待てました
Finally!
ごつぁん
≪くそ今度はこのチビ囮か≫
Shit. The midget was just a decoy this time.
And here I thought it was coming my way!
俺に上がると思たのに
(田中)どうだらきょう君
How'd you like that, turnip head?
I told you to decide after you've watched him play!
試合で見てみろて言たろ
(金田一)く
うわ俺打つ気満々で
｢なんだと｣とか叫んじゃたよ
I went all like, "Say what?" thinking I'd get to spike! So embarrassing!
恥ずかしい
いいんだよそれで
That's perfectly fine.
お前が本気で跳ぶから
相手もつられて跳ぶんだろ
It's because you jump for real
that you lure the opponents in.
Is that how it works?
そういうもん
そういうもんだ
It is.
くそ
(岩泉)焦んなよ金田一
Shit.
Don't lose your cool, Kindaichi.
こちの攻撃だて
ちゃんと決まてる
We're scoring plenty of points ourselves.
Don't let them get to you.
のまれるな
おす
Okay!
お
へえ
Even I can tell that they're splitting the blockers up.
素人目にもブロクが
分散させられてんのが分かるよ
烏野て
こんな強いとこだけ
I had no idea Karasuno had such a strong team.
ほぐ
日向ボケェ
But they mess up a lot too, don't they?
でもミスも多いよね
(生徒たち)おお
Huddle up!
(岩泉)集合
(青城一同)おす
Okay!
どうした日向
What's up, Hinata?
Back when I played my first match,
俺初めて試合に出たときは
I thought I had to do everything all by myself.
全部自分で
ちゃんとやんなきゃて思てて
Going good!
But now I have players much
better than myself around me.
でも今は俺よりずと
うまい選手が周りにいるから
Keep this up!
You can count on us!
So all I can do right now is believe in them and jump, right?
今の俺にできるのは
信じて跳ぶことだけですよね
There was no need at all to rack my brain.
ごちゃごちゃ考えなくて
よかたんですね
あ
遅ぇよ
You sure took your time!
You have no idea what an unbelievable weapon that belief and jumping ability is.
その信じて跳ぶことが
とんでもない武器なんだけどな
(矢巾)おい金田一
話違うじゃねぇかあの影山
Dude, Kindaichi.
Kageyama's nothing like you said he was!
(金田一)お俺だて
あんなの初めて見て
I-I've never seen anything like this either.
影山のあのムチャぶりトスに
合わせられるｽﾊﾟｲｶｰがいるなんて
I can't believe there's a spiker who can keep up with his unreasonable sets.
You're mistaken.
(入畑)それは違うな
あの５番は全く
ボルを見てないように見える
It seems to me like that number five isn't looking at the ball at all.
(金田一)監督あのどういう
What do you mean, Coach?
(入畑)影山が振り下ろされる
手のひらピンポイントに
I think Kageyama's making pinpoint sets into the palm of his hand.
ボルを合わせているんだと思う
Is that even possible?
(岩泉)そんなことが可能なのか
Kageyama of all people consciously working together with someone?
あの影山が他人に合わせてる
That must mean that number five has enough ability
(入畑)噂に聞く自己中心的で
プライドが高い影山に
to make the supposedly egocentric and prideful Kageyama do that.
そうさせるほどの能力が
あの５番には
あるてことなんだろうな
If you want to know what's really amazing, it's that he trusts Kageyama's sets completely as he jumps.
何がすごいて
１００％影山のトスを信じて
跳んでるてことだよ
ボルは
ここに上がてくると
He's certain that the ball will come to him.
ブロクふられても
レシブしかり上げてけ
Even if they break free of our blocks, make sure to dig it out!
We've put out our best available lineup, you know!
こちだて
今出せるベストメンバなんだ
Show some pride!
プライド見せろよ
(一同)はい
Yes, sir!
ふぅ
(溝口)すごいですね影山
Okay, time to turn things around!
Kageyama's amazing.
Yeah!
It's too bad we couldn't get him to join us.
やぱうちで取れなかたのは
痛かたですね
We did make him an offer, right?
声は掛けてたんですよね
うん
Yeah.
But even if he had joined us, that doesn't
necessarily mean he would've still played like that.
でも影山が
うちに来たからといて
あんなふうなプレを
してくれたかは分からないよ
え
(入畑)烏野だたから
Maybe it's because he picked Karasuno...
Let's keep going and take this set!
because he's playing with that number five that he's playing the way he is right now.
あの５番がいたからこその
今の影山なのかもしれない
Dude, that hurt!
Just trying to fire you up.
あはあ
Hey, it's time.
Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
トン
(澤村)チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
(田中)月島
Tsukishima!
ピ
よしゃ
Yes!
Nicely done, Tsukki!
(山口)ツキナイス
ナイス月島
Good job, Tsukishima!
Your sets are so precise it gives me the creeps.
お前のトス精密すぎて気持ち悪
ああ
There's probably a better way to put it,
but I can kinda see where Tsukishima's coming from.
≪言い方はあれだけど
月島の言うことは少し分かるな≫
Maybe I should aim for your glasses next time.
Just try it. You'll get thrown out of the gym again.
By the time you think you want the ball to come to a certain point, it's already there.
≪ここに来ればいいなて
思た所に
すでにある感じなんだよな
ボルが≫
I'll do it on the sly.
Like hell you can!
It's terrifying, but also really reassuring.
≪またく末恐ろしいでも
Are you stupid?
(澤村)
試合中だしそこまでにしようか
That's enough. We're in the middle of a match.
田中ナイサ
はあなるほど
Give us a good serve, Tanaka.
A good one!
I see.
Tanaka
Hinata
Sawamura
Kageyama
Tsukishima
Ennoshita
Sugawara
Yamaguchi
Kinoshita
Narita
点を取てｻｰﾌﾞ権を獲得する度に
The lineup rotates every time we score and gain the serve.
ロテシｮンが回ていて今は
And right now, we have Kageyama, Tsukishima, and Ennoshita in front.
影山君月島君縁下君が前衛か
(菅原)
はい今は試合スタト時と
Yeah.
It's the exact opposite of the formation we started the match in.
ちょうど
逆の立ち位置になてますね
When Hinata plays in front, his distractions raise the efficiency of our offense.
日向君が前衛にいるときは
彼の囮のおかげで
全体の攻撃決定率が上がり
On the other hand, when Tsukishima plays in front...
逆に月島君が上がてくると
おお
青城チムに負けず劣らずの
we'll have blockers just as overpowering as Seijou!
なんとも威圧的なブロクだね
君はブロクも得意なんだけ
でもあんま出しゃばんないでね
I hear you're good at blocking too,
but you'd better know your place.
てめぇこそ
吹飛ばされんじゃねぇぞ
And you'd better make sure you don't get blown away,
what with you being as thin as a twig.
ヒョロヒョロしやがて
(縁下)
ケケンカすんなよな
Stop fighting, guys.
(田中)敵は
ネトの向こうだつうの
Hey! Your opponents are the guys on the other side!
おい来るぞ
Watch out! Here they come!
(岩泉)う
よし
Yeah!
(月島)ちょと
今止めたの僕なんだけど
Hey, I was the one who blocked that.
ああ俺の手にも当たた
Say what? It hit my hand too.
お前らいいかげんにしろ
Knock it off already!
Serves you two right.
≪どちもざまぁ
怒られてやんの≫
What are you smirking for?
何ニヤニヤしてる
影山やめろ
Stop that, Kageyama!
(渡)く
くそ
Dammit.
Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
焦てきた
We're starting to lose our cool.
おい今のカバ入れたろうが
国見ボケェ
Hey, Kunimi! You could've covered for that, fool!
やぱりあの５番
止めないことにはなんとも
I think we need to stop that number five somehow.
Sure, Kageyama and number five form a formidable duo,
確かに
影山と５番のコンビは脅威だが
but that's not all.
それ以外にも
冷静さは足りないが
パワと気概あふれる
Tanaka needs to be a bit more level-headed,
but he's a great spiker with tons of power and spirit.
スパイカの田中君
若干覇気に欠けるが
クレバなブロカの月島君
Tsukishima seems a bit too relaxed, but he's a very clever blocker.
穴の多い守備を広くカバする
キャプテンの澤村君
And the captain, Sawamura, more than makes up for their leaky defense.
Send it my way!
素人まがいはいるし
守備はまだまだ穴だらけだが
They have an extremely green player on their team,
and their defense is full of holes,
その素人まがいを軸にした
変幻自在の攻撃
but they have a flexible offense built around that greenhorn.
This is what you call toying with another team.
(入畑)
翻弄するとはまさにこのこと
Karasuno, huh?
烏野かちぐはぐで危うくて
A bunch of unsteady misfits,
(一同)しゃあ
(入畑)面白いチムだ
but an amusing team.
Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
ああ
セト取られちゃた
They took the set!
(金田一)くそ
(縁下)ナイストス影山
Damn it!
Hell yeah!
Nice set, Kageyama.
Thank you.
あざす
(田中)このまま最終セｯト取るぞ
Let's keep this up and win the last set!
Good thing they don't have anyone who serves like Kageyama.
A comeback victory!
Victory!
Yeah. We're not too good at receiving.
Thanks.
We can't let our guards down.
This is just a hunch, but I don't think they're playing their starting setter—
(縁下)向こうに影山みたいな
サブ打つヤツいなくて
Oh, you're back, Oikawa.
よかたですね
(澤村)ああ
うちはお世辞にもレシブ
うまいとは言えないからな
Next Episode Preview
What? Seijou weren't playing their starting setter?
サンキュ
油断ダメです
Who's that pretty boy, anyway?
(日向･田中)勝利勝利
たぶんですけど
向こうのセタ
You know him, right, Kageyama?
Well, you'll have to wait and see.
正セタじゃ
(女生徒たち)きゃあ
Episode Seven:
Versus the Great King
(入畑)おお戻たのか及川
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"Versus the Great King."
え
青城正セタじゃなかたの
(田中)それよりあいつ誰なんだよ
あのニヤけたヤツ
影山なんか知てんだろ
それは見てのお楽しみです